Leah: Early computer codes date back
to the 19th Century and many modern
programming languages stem from 'Ada
Lovelace's first machine algorithm'
which was developed for Charles
Babbage's Difference machine in 1843.
It was the 1940's that the first modern
computers were created along with
machine-specific assembly language.
However, it was the 1950's that the first
modern programming language was born.
This was FORTRAN short
for formula translator.
Others were to follow such as
LISP - list processor,
ALGOL -algorithmic language
and COBOL -common
business-oriented language.
In the 1960's BASIC had been
invented and then C was released.
Unix was developed in the 1970’s
and it’s code rewritten in ‘C’ in
1972, the first major OS or operating
system not in assembly language.
Linux first released in 1991 is
written almost entirely in C and both
Windows and macOS both contain C.
The 1990’s also welcomed some of today’s
most recognisable languages such as
Python, Java, Java Script and PHP.
Which opened the world to social media,
Android/OS apps and streaming services.
To learn more, take a look at the
website further down on this page…